{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is the best password, according to the lecture?",
            "correctAnswer": "kent.SU2018",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "$starwars",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "p4$$w0rd",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Frank2000"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does CIA stand for?",
            "correctAnswer": "Confidentiality, Integrity, Availability",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Confidence, Impenetrability, Assurance",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Covert Information Access",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Cybersecurity Infiltration Analysis"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does confidentiality, in the context of cybersecurity, mean?",
            "correctAnswer": "Only authorized parties can access a particular asset.",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Encrypting all your data to make it acccessible to everyone",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Making information avaliable to anyone who requests it",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Ensuring information is kept secret to gain a competitive advantage"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does integrity, in the context of cybersecurity, mean?",
            "correctAnswer": "Only authorized parties can modify, create, and delete assets.",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Deleting assets to reduce clutter",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Randomly altering assets to keep them unpredictable",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Allow assets to be deleted by anyone without restrictions"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does availability, in the context of cybersecurity, mean?",
            "correctAnswer": "Preventing downtime of systems or inability to access data/information.",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Sharing sensitive data",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Maintaining a strict schedule for system maintence",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Encrypting data"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does 'non-repudiation' mean, in the context of information security?",
            "correctAnswer": "Ability for parties to prove that a message has been sent/received by a specific person",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Process of concealing the identity of a sender / recipient",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Act of encrypting data to prvent anyone from accessing it",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Allow parties to deny who sent / recieved a message"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the best definition of a vulnerability?",
            "correctAnswer": "A weakness or flaw in a system, that can be exploited by malicious actors.",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Refers to the physical damage caused by external factors",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Any software that enhances the performance of a system or application",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "?"
        },
        {
            "question": "A tech company is trying to secure it's sensitive data from unauthorized access. What is the best way to do this?",
            "correctAnswer": "Encryption",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Firewall",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Antivirus",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Authentication"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term used for individuals who enjoy watching and posting provactive messages",
            "correctAnswer": "Eyeball",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Haters",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Lolcows",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Bzzters"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the most prevalent form of cyberattack?",
            "correctAnswer": "Social engineering",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "DoS",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Malware",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Phishing"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is password hashing?",
            "correctAnswer": "Converting a password into a fixed-length strong of characters using a mathemetical algorithm",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Storing passwords in plain text format",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Encrypting a password with a secret key for secure storage",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Randomly generating a password for user authentication"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a common issue with biometric authentication systems?",
            "correctAnswer": "Match key points aganist a saved template, leading to false postivies / false positives",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Limited accuracy in distinguishing between identical twins",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "High susceptibility to brute force attacks",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Inability to adapt to changes in user appearance over time"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the most common 'route' to cybercrime?",
            "correctAnswer": "Online gaming forums",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Educational websites",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "E-commerce websites",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Professional networking sites"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is white hat hacking associated with?",
            "correctAnswer": "Ethical hacking practices to identify and rectify security vulnerabilities",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Unauthorized infiltration into systems for personal gain",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Conducting cyber attacks to exploit security weaknesses",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Interpretive dance and performing arts"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of security attack involves an unauthorized party gaining access to an asset without permission?",
            "correctAnswer": "Interception/Eavesdropping",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Modification attack",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Fabrication attack",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Interruption attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "What security breach occurs when an unauthorized party alters the value in a database or file?",
            "correctAnswer": "Modification Attack",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Interception/Eavesdropping",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Interruption",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Fabrication attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of security attacks, what does interception/eavesdropping primarily involve?",
            "correctAnswer": "Unauthorized access to confidential information",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Destroying data files",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Modifying software programs",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Inserting counterfeit objects into the system"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of security attack includes the insertion of counterfeit objects into the system, such as fake emails for phishing websites?",
            "correctAnswer": "Fabrication attack",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Modification attack",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Interruption attack",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Interception/Eavesdropping"
        },
        {
            "question": "When an unauthorized party destroys or makes an asset unavailable, what type of security attack is being executed?",
            "correctAnswer": "Interruption attack",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Fabrication attack",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Modification Attack",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Interception / Eavesdropping"
        },
        {
            "question": "A company is looking to enhance its security measures by making its system more user-friendly. Which concept best describes this security approach?",
            "correctAnswer": "Usable Security",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Inaccessible Protection",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Robust Isolation",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Elusive Safeguarding"
        },
        {
            "question": "A study aims to investigate the predictability of user behavior while creating graphical passwords. What method does this align with?",
            "correctAnswer": "Cognitive Walkthrough",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Heuristic Evaluation",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "User Testing",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Expert Inspection"
        },
        {
            "question": "An organization aims to design security systems visible and accessible to users. What guideline does this reflect, in the context of security usability?",
            "correctAnswer": "Making Security Visible",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Concealing Security Measures",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Complicating Access",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Hiding Security Functions"
        },
        {
            "question": "An attacker gains unauthorized access to a wireless network and eavesdrops on the communication between two devices to obtain sensitive information. What form of cyberattack is this?",
            "correctAnswer": "Eavesdropping",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Denial of Service (DoS)",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Phishing",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Man-in-the-Middle (MitM)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which term refers to malware that uses encryption to hold a victim's data at ransom, demanding payment for decryption?",
            "correctAnswer": "Ransomware",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Spyware",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Trojan Horse",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Worm"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the term 'social engineering' primarily refer to?",
            "correctAnswer": "Manipulating individuals to divulge confidential information",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Encryption of sensitive data",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Exploiting software vulnerabilities",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Denying access to unauthorized users"
        },
        {
            "question": "A company seeks to safeguard systems and networks against prevalent cyber attacks. Which framework offers a prioritized set of safeguards for this purpose?",
            "correctAnswer": "CIS Controls",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "NIST",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "ISO",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "IEEE"
        },
        {
            "question": "A company is planning to secure its systems by controlling access to data and services. Which step from the NCSC 10 Steps to Cyber Security should they prioritize?",
            "correctAnswer": "Identity and access management",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Incident management",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Vulnerability management",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Architecture and configuration"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a discretionary access control (DAC) policy, access is controlled based on:",
            "correctAnswer": "The identity of the requestor and access rules.",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Access rules determined by a central authority.",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Access rules determined by roles",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "A"
        },
        {
            "question": "A company's data is accessible to all employees, and each employee has the discretion to grant or deny access to their files. Which access control policy is primarily in use here?",
            "correctAnswer": "Discretionary access control (DAC)",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Role-based access control (RBAC)",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Attribute-based access control (ABAC)",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Mandatory access control (MAC)"
        },
        {
            "question": "What access control policy is based on the roles that users have within the system?",
            "correctAnswer": "Role-based access control (RBAC)",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Attribute-based access control (ABAC)",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "The user's job title and organizational hierarchy",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "The time of day and the system's current workload"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a highly regulated government agency, access to sensitive data is determined by specific rules established by a central authority. Which access control policy is likely to be enforced here?",
            "correctAnswer": "MAC",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "ABAC",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "DAC",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "RBAC"
        },
        {
            "question": "What access control policy takes into account the attributes of entities and the environment relevant to a request?",
            "correctAnswer": "ABAC",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "DAC",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "RBAC",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "MAC"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does unauthorized access to computer material mean in the Computer Misuse Act (1990)?",
            "correctAnswer": "Knowingly accessing a computer that you are not allowed to.",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Accessing computer material after accidentally stumbling upon it online",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Legitimate use of computer material",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Accessing computer material with explicit permission"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why might a disgruntled employee be held liable when intentionally launching a computer virus in the company's network, causing temporary disruption to the email system?",
            "correctAnswer": "As there was intent to impair the computer's operation.",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Because it was an accidental act",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Due to unintentional consequences",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "To facilitate system improvement"
        },
        {
            "question": "What illicit activity is a hacker engaged in when they develop and sell a specialized tool designed to circumvent firewall systems and gain unauthorized access to computer networks?",
            "correctAnswer": "Unauthorized access facilitation",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Cybersecurity awareness training",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Ethical Hacking",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Legally providing network security consultation"
        },
        {
            "question": "An attacker injects malicious code into a legitimate website, which runs on vistors' browsers. What attack is this?",
            "correctAnswer": "Cross site scripting (XSS)",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Server spoofing",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Data Leakage",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Digital impersonation"
        },
        {
            "question": "An attacker disguses themselves as a legit users to access sensitive information by tricking a system admin, what attack is this?",
            "correctAnswer": "Privilege escalation",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Malware Infection",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Network Reconnaissance",
            "incorrectAnswer3": "Encryption evasion"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the NCSC's 10 Steps, what does 'identity and access management' primarily aim to control?",
            "correctAnswer": "Who / what can access systems and data",
            "incorrectAnswer1": "Destorying data files",
            "incorrectAnswer2": "Forbidding privilege escalation"
        }
        
    ]
}